TEN (ENVELOPE)
[narrator] Ten:
The ability to envelop your body
in a shroud of Nen aura,
making it tougher and slowing
the effects of aging.
ZETSU (SUPPRESS)
Zetsu: A technique which
shuts off your flow of Nen aura.
Effective for concealing your presence
and recovering from fatigue.
REN (REFINE)
Ren: A technique for creating
an especially strong Nen aura.
It is crucial for increasing your power.
HATSU (RELEASE)
Hatsu: The release of your Nen aura,
after using Ren to boost it.
These four elements are known
as the Four Exercises
and are critical to the mastery of Nen.
FOUR EXERCISES
[theme song playing]
[cheering]
[Gon] I’m really sorry, Mr. Wing.
But I’m itching for a fight right now!
FIERCE x AND x FEROCIOUS
[narrator] Gon faces his first match
on the 200th floor,
but is caught off guard
by his opponent’s unconventional attack.
[cackling]
[cries out in pain]
And another top hits him from behind!
It looks like he’s in big trouble now
because he’s just been surrounded
by the Dancing Tops!
[grunts]
[cries out in pain]
That’s a clean hit and knockdown!
For two points!
[commentator]
Gido’s up to an early four-point lead!
-Can you fight?
-You bet!
There are too many tops for me
to be able to keep track of all of them.
Dammit!
What should I do?
[Zushi] M-- Master…
Is he using Nen right now?
[Wing] Yes. That’s a form of Hatsu.
He’s projecting his aura into the tops.
That is what allows the tops
to move around with significantly
more strength and speed
than would normally be possible.
[Wing] Small objects require
only a small amount of aura.
The larger the object,
the more aura is necessary.
And I wouldn’t be surprised
if Gido gave the tops
extra Nen for good measure.
That’s because
letting the tops spin on their own
without the benefit of additional aura,
wouldn’t pack much of a punch.
He can do this
because he feels great personal affinity
with them.
Nothing has more of an impact
on an object’s response
than strong emotional attachment.
[grunting]
I can’t follow them with my eyes.
The tops have been charged with Nen.
I have to sense their presence!
Yeah. I feel it!
My Ten is fading!
[groans]
[commentator] Another direct hit!
Gon is completely helpless!
He’s been knocked clear out of the ring!
[Gon grunts]
[commentator] The score is now six-zero!
He’s dug himself quite a hole!
[Gon] It’s no use.
If I focus on sensing the tops,
I neglect my Ten and it seeps away…
So, what should I--?
A top bounced outside the ring…
But... it’s not attacking me…
What's wrong?
Can you continue on with the match?
Be quiet, okay?
I’m trying to think here!
If you’re not back in the ring
by the count of ten, you lose!
One!
Now that I think about it,
the Nen in this top didn’t feel malicious.
What about all the others?
They’re just spinning
around the ring randomly
and bumping into each other.
Maybe the tops aren’t really
coming after me at all.
Four!
How come you’re standing
outside of the ring?
Because if I stayed up there in the ring,
I’d probably end up getting hurt, too!
-And Five!
-That’s it!
It’s just like a game of ‘sumo tops’!
[Wing] It’s impossible to command
regular tops to move with precision.
It’s much more likely
that Gido commands them
to strike down anything in their way.
They spin around the ring,
striking anything unfortunate enough
to cross their paths.
Seven!
If the tops aren’t aiming for me,
I don’t have to fear them so much!
I can ignore them
and attack Gido directly!
[scoffs]
[Gido] You may have figured out my tops,
but you still can’t land an attack on me!
[commentator] There it is!
Gido’s special technique,
combining offense and defense!
Tornado Top!
[screams]
[commentator]
Whoa! Gon gets hit with a vicious counter!
Three points!
The judge has awarded
a critical hit and knockdown!
Gido has nine points!
Gon is on the brink of defeat!
[straining]
[cackling]
[Gido] I turn into a top to protect myself
and let my Dancing Tops
handle the offense!
It’s a conservative strategy
but it’s effective
for racking up the points!
[Wing]
There are a number of ways to defeat Gido.
You can attack him until he tires
and his Ten begins to fade.
Or you can use Hatsu
to overpower his defense.
Both of those methods would require
an extremely large amount of aura.
But Gon doesn’t know Ren yet…
the technique
for generating aura instantly.
Learning how to create
large amounts of aura quickly
and how to channel it into attacks...
That requires endless training
and combat experience
in order to learn.
Gon has neither.
He’d need five more years to fight Gido.
I’m sure that’s beginning to dawn on him.
What should I do?
How am I gonna prolong this match?
If he scores one more point,
it’s over.
But I want to keep fighting!
What can I do right now?
I got it.
[mumbles]
Gon!
[Wing] He released his Ten?!
That’s so reckless!
But he didn’t just release it…
That’s…
Zetsu!
The technique
for concealing your presence!
All the nodes are closed
and there is no aura!
Even the normal,
faint leak of aura is closed off,
leaving him no defense against Nen!
I didn’t teach him Zetsu.
Did he learn it before we met?
If that’s the case,
he wouldn’t know that this is Zetsu.
He probably picked it up naturally
on his own,
just like how beasts in nature
learn it to hunt their prey!
He certainly has incredible potential.
But why would he use it now… here?
You idiot!
What if you get hit by another Nen attack?
Without protection,
that’ll totally mess you up!
[Gon] I know that.
But… if I’m gonna track
the tops’ complex movements
with only feelings to go on,
then I need to focus all of my senses.
Could it be that he never intended
to win this match?
He’s risking everything…
He’s risking his own life…
to train?!
[cackling]
[Gido] Do you have a death wish, kid?
Then here! Let me give you what you want!
[Gido] What?
[cheering]
[commentator] Amazing!
That’s the first time Gon
has managed to evade an attack!
[Gon] I can feel them.
I know where they’re heading!
This is all I can do right now.
Just concentrate
on dodging my opponent’s attacks!
[mumbles]
At least this way I can still fight!
[Killua] Your right radius and your ulna
were both broken.
A fractured humerus.
Three broken ribs.
Not to mention
twelve other minor fractures.
It’ll take four months to heal.
You moron!
Sorry!
[yells] Well, an apology isn’t gonna help!
Don’t you have any brains in there
at all?!
Didn’t you see what happened
to all the guys who went through it?
The Nen initiation?
One wrong move and you would have
ended up like them!
It coulda been a lot worse,
so you’re lucky.
Man. How come you think
Four-Eyes was training us
in the first place?
[Gon] [chuckles nervously]
Still...
I had a feeling that it’d be okay.
I mean, sure, I took a few hits.
But he missed my vital spots,
so no big deal.
[groans]
[rasping in pain]
[knocking]
Come in!
[Gon exhales in relief]
Oh! Four-Eyes!
[Gon] Uh, I’m sor--
Apologizing to me isn't going to help!
What on earth were you thinking?!
Didn’t you see the ones
who went through the Nen initiation?
You could easily
have ended up just like them!
[Killua]
Yeah. I just told him the same thing.
[Wing sighs]
Honestly…
I’m glad it wasn’t any worse.
[Gon] I’m sorry, Mr. Wing.
I really am.
-I’m not letting this slide.
-[Gon] Huh?
Killua. Do you know when Gon
will be completely recovered?
The doctor said
it’d take about two months.
[Wing] I see.
Thanks a lot, Killua.
In that case,
I won’t allow you to participate
in any matches for two months.
Nor will I allow the study of or training
in the use of Nen.
If you choose not to abide
by these conditions,
then you will never
receive instruction from me again.
Understand?
[Gon] Yes, sir. I’ll do as you say.
Your left hand.
This is a promise thread.
Its purpose is to remind you
of the promise you made.
Okay.
Killua. A word.
[Wing] So tell me…
what is the true goal
that you and Gon are pursuing here?
[Killua]
Well, we don’t really have a goal.
Before we ran into you and Zushi,
I just wanted to earn some quick cash.
Gon wants to beat a guy named Hisoka,
so he’s here to train.
And that’s it.
Everyone on the 200th floor
just wants to reach the top floor.
The Battle Olympia. Right?
Yeah, I’m not too interested.
But Gon, though…
Well… I’m not so sure.
He says he doesn’t care what happens,
as long as he gets to fight Hisoka.
But after yesterday’s match…
I don't know.
I get the feeling
he just enjoys the thrill.
[cheering]
[commentator] How long this back-and-forth
is going to go on
is anybody’s guess!
There are nearly fifty tops
literally flying around the ring!
It's a terrifying whirlwind
of spinning tops!
But Gon is evading all of them!
With all of his tops already in play,
Gido can only watch with the rest of us!
[yells] No, not that way!
Oh, no! There’s nowhere to run!
[grunts]
[Wing] That situation could very well
have cost him his life
and he was enjoying it?
[Killua] Yeah. And I would know.
I’ve felt the same way before myself.
But at least I pick and choose my battles.
Once he’s in the zone,
he loses sight of everything else.
Oh! But he’s not the type
to break the same promise twice,
so don't worry.
[Wing] Oh, dear.
What have I done?
[Killua] It's too late.
We already know all the facts.
Gon and me both.
If you regret teaching us
and want to back out,
we’ll find somebody else.
Or we’ll simply learn it ourselves.
You don't have to feel responsible.
My brother can use Nen.
Hisoka can, too.
So Gon and I were bound
to find out about it eventually.
I understand.
I intend to finish what I started.
There are so many more things
that I have yet to teach you.
Zushi is waiting in my room.
You can train with him, if you’d like.
[Killua] Nah. I’ll pass.
Hm?
I don't want to leave Gon behind.
If he can keep his promise,
we’ll train together.
Give him a message for me, then!
Tell him I will let him
practice the other ‘Nen’, the flame!
And tell him to work on Ten daily!
Hey, Gon.
[Wing] Master...
It was never my intention, but…
have I…
Have I awoken a terrible monster?
[Zushi] Master?
[Kurapika] What’s going on?
[Rei] You found this agency on your own,
and that tells me you’re pretty sharp.
Even so…
I can’t introduce you
to our valued clients.
And it’s not because
of your total lack of experience.
Some of our clients
don’t seem to mind that.
The thing is...
experience isn’t all you lack.
But what do you mean?
Like I told you,
I already have a Hunter’s License.
[Rei] Maybe. But your Exam isn’t over yet.
It’s obvious.
Excuse me?
-[Rei] Can you see anything?
-Huh?
Like next to me, I mean.
Can’t see a thing, can you?
You come back when you can...
and not before.
That’s the minimum requirement here.
What does she mean?
What is it that I can’t see?
[thunder rolling]
[electricity buzzes]
[man] You can’t see it,
but you can sense it, huh?
-[Kurapika] Why did you do that?
-[man] This?
Oh. I was just playing around.
[thunder]
This must be fate,
us crossing paths. Y’think?
Try to think of this as...
a little bit of friendly advice
from a senior.
You didn’t notice when I stole this,
or when I walked right past you, either.
You’re totally clueless.
Bastard!
Give me back my license right now!
Does a newbie who knows nothing of Nen
have a chance of beating me?
Nen, huh?
[scoffs]
[thunder]
Wanna give it a try?
[rain patters]
[Kurapika panting]
Do you get it now?
There’s something important
you still lack.
[Kurapika grunts] I...
I need...
[shouts]
I need enough power to fight on my own!
[man] Come with me.
I’ll teach you.
The real exam has just begun.
[narrator] Gon’s hidden potential
is beginning to awaken.
And Kurapika
has also encountered a new power.
One that he hopes
will help propel him forward.
[theme song playing]
[Gon] Coming up:
-Gon...
-[Killua] ...and Killua’s…
[both] Hunterpedia!
-I’m Gon!
-I’m Killua!
[both] And this is our Hunterpedia!
Today, we're introducing
the Hunter Agency!
This place helps pro Hunters find work,
but it was really hard for Kurapika
to find the office that he visited.
Gotta find the agency
before you qualify as a pro Hunter.
[Gon] Next time:
Destiny x and x Tenacity.
[Killua]
I wonder who Four-Eyes is, anyway?
[Gon] Hmm...
I wonder who the Floor Masters are.
[Killua gasps]
[Killua and Gon] Could it be?!